Darren Johnston

Phone: 07904525333 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/darren-johnston-347a9417b

Email: djohns206@caledonian.ac.uk GitHub: https://github.com/Daz9
Portfolio: http://darrenjohnston.info

#Summary

Software developer with experience in working on a variety of products ranging from booking platforms in the travel industry to ecommerce sites in the household appliance spare parts market.

I have received strong feedback from various colleagues in my career stating that my positive attitude towards work and strong communication skills, have made me a valuable asset to the teams I have worked in.

I am always on the lookout to try new things and grow my skills. With a current focus on becoming a more well-rounded full stack developer.

#Skills			
Front-End	Back End	Workflow/Source control	Frameworks
HTML	Perl	Git	Catalyst
CSS	Bash	SVN	Moose
JavaScript	MySQL	GitLab/GitHub	Flask
	Python	Jira/Confluence	
	AWS	Jenkins	

#Professional Experience

TravelTek / Full-stack developer

August 2019 - March 2021: Glasgow | Hybrid

- Joined and assisted a team in migrating from our legacy infrastructure to AWS.
- Interfaced with a client's API to develop a cruise booking journey for our main platform.
- Transitioned into a maintenance role after the covid lockdowns to improve the platforms stability as the travel industry opened back up.

Connect Distribution / Perl developer

March 2021 – Current: Birmingham | Remote

- Coordinated closely with the warehouse management and QA teams to roll out a change to the address fields we request from international customers when placing an order.
- Worked with various stakeholders in the business to roll out Trustpilot integration to our international sites.
- Executed a number of changes to our DPD delivery processes to support orders to Europe post Brexit.
- Investigated and created resources to help my team work efficiently with plugins to support Perl development.
- Designed and implemented the processes required to add a new delivery provider to cover orders to Northern Ireland.

#Education

BSc (Hons) Software Development for Business: 1st class

2015 -2019: Glasgow Caledonian University

#Projects

Portfolio Website:

My portfolio site is hosted on AWS with various AWS services integrated into it.

- The contact me box is implemented using API gateway and lambda to forward messages to my inbox.
- Googles ReCAPTCHA implemented as a serverless lambda call to verify the user before forwarding a message to me.
- The site itself is hosted on S3 with Route 53 managing the DNS name.
- Code pipeline is used to implement a CICD process to deploy changes I commit to the repo automatically.

Honours project:

Nominated by GCU for young software engineer of the year award: Scotsoft 2019.

Supporting mobility for the visually impaired by developing a prototype device to perform object recognition and temperature sensing on household items.

Implemented in Python using TensorFlow with a thermal camera module to measure temperature from a short distance. I modelled a 3d printed shell using AutoCAD to hold the prototype.

#Interests

I have an interest in 3D printing, VR and I like to go running which I've done a lot more of since going remote for work.